# NICOLAS MAVRIDES

Manchester, UK · +44 7873232548

nicmavr1@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/nicolas-mavrides-722a62139/ · nicolasmavrides.co.uk

Computer Science graduate from the University of Sheffield with work experience in the industry. As a dedicated Software Engineer, I always aim for maximum success & quality in any given task. I maintain an open and upbeat approach to learning about new technologies, and make sure that every experience counts by reflection and critical self-evaluation.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**SEPTEMBER 2018 – MAY 2020** 

#### COMPUTER LAB DEMONSTRATOR, UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD, SHEFFIELD, UK

Assisting 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> year Computer Science students in practical labs for Ruby and Java programming, by providing support on exercises and answering any questions that may arise

**JUNE 2017 - JUNE 2018** 

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, ROLLS-ROYCE PLC, BIRMINGHAM, UK

A 12-month internship as a member of the Software Development team which was tasked with delivery of software solutions to various teams throughout the company. My internship involved development and thorough testing of coded solutions in the C# and Python languages, and ensuring software developed was of appropriate standard by liaising between teams

## **EDUCATION**

**SEPTEMBER 2015 – JUNE 2020** 

#### THE UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD, SHEFFIELD, UK

Currently enrolled on a 5-year Master of Computer Science degree with a Year in Industry. Predicted final grade of minimum 2:1, with current average grade of 69%. Successfully completed dissertation project which consisted of an Internet of Things (IoT) solution for measuring air quality and pollution levels.

**SEPTEMBER 2008 – JUNE 2014** 

#### THE GC SCHOOL OF CAREERS, NICOSIA, CYPRUS

Completed European Computer Driving License (ECDL) course and A-levels in Greek language, Mathematics, ICT and Physics. A-level grades attained: A, B, B and C respectively.

#### SPOKEN LANGUAGES

- English Native Grade A in IGCSE English as a First Language by Cambridge Uni. Examinations
- Greek Fluent Grade A in A-level Greek language by Edexcel Examinations
- Turkish Basic Self-taught

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Object-Orientated programming: Java, Python, Ruby, C, C++ and C#
- Web development: HTML/CSS, Javascript/Node.js, Ruby On Rails, PHP
- Mobile Development: use of Android Studio with Java and Room
- Microsoft Office Applications
- Solidworks CAD Software

- Databases:
   MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Operating systems:
   Windows: versions 7 10
   Linux: Ubuntu, Raspbian, Fedora
- Internet of Things (IoT):
   Building of microcontroller circuits & programming with Arduino C/C++

# **CONFERENCES / ACTIVITIES**

- Capco Build Your Own Bank Hackathon | <a href="https://www.capco.com/Solutions/Capco-Digital/Build-a-digital-bank-from-scratch">https://www.capco.com/Solutions/Capco-Digital/Build-a-digital-bank-from-scratch</a> | London, UK | September 2019
   Participant in hackathon organized by Capco Digital with the aim of developing a customer loyalty scheme for a digital bank
- International Student Week in Belgrade 2019 | <a href="http://www.iswib.org/">http://www.iswib.org/</a> | Belgrade, Serbia | July 2019
  - Participant in game development workshop using Unity and C# programming
- Istanbul Tech Talks 2018 | <a href="http://www.istanbultechtalks.com/">http://www.istanbultechtalks.com/</a> | Istanbul, Turkey | April 2018 | Conference on various software development topics, hosted by Istanbul Technical University
- FOSDEM 2018 | https://fosdem.org/ | Brussels, Belgium | February 2018
  Open-source developer conference, hosted by Université libre de Bruxelles
- Freenode #live 2017 | <a href="https://freenode.live/">https://freenode.live/</a> | Bristol, UK | November 2017
   Open-source projects conference, organized and hosted on behalf of the Freenode IRC network
- ShefJam4 | http://shefjam.com/ | Sheffield, UK | March 2017 24-hour Game Jam event, hosted by the University of Sheffield Computer Science Society.
- Engineering You're Hired! 2017 | <a href="http://www.yourehired.group.shef.ac.uk/wp/">http://www.yourehired.group.shef.ac.uk/wp/</a> | Sheffield, UK | January 2017
  - Week-long group project at the Uni. of Sheffield on developing an Augmented Reality headset for extreme sports
- HackSheffield 2016 | <a href="https://www.hacksheffield.co/">https://www.hacksheffield.co/</a> | Sheffield, UK | October 2016
   24-hour Hackathon, hosted by the University of Sheffield
- Google Hash Code 2016 | <a href="https://hashcode.withgoogle.com/">https://hashcode.withgoogle.com/</a> | Sheffield, UK | February 2016
   Participated in a team of fellow students to solve the "Optimization of Drone Deliveries" problem given by Google
- GEC Week 2016 | <a href="https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/civil/ug/global-engineering-challenge/">https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/civil/ug/global-engineering-challenge/</a> | Sheffield, UK | January 2016
  - Week-long project at the University of Sheffield on tackling electricity shortages in Africa with an engineering solution "Electrical Supply Infrastructure with Renewable Sources"